Patrik Billgert Högalidsgatan 46A 117 30, Stockholm, Sweden Email/LinkedIn/Portfolio



PROFILE

Versatile, open-minded and self-propelled developer that highly values a great user experience. Ten years experience in developing applications for the App Store. Been working with many different types of companies ranging from local startups to global brands.

Passionate about infrastructure and design. Enjoy working with automation, optimization, experimentation, scalability, architecture & new technologies. Always learning and continuously trying to enforce simplicity when programming & designing apps.

SKILLS

Main

Swift, Objective-C, Xcode, Cocoa Touch, UIKit, SwiftUI, WatchKit, WidgetKit, Core Data, AVFoundation, Core Location, MVC, MVVM, CocoaPods, Swift Package Manager, Git, CI/CD, Xcode Cloud, GitHub Actions, Fastlane, Scrum, JIRA, Asana, Figma, Photoshop, UX/UI design, Product development, Project management

Secondary

C#, Javascript, Unity3D, React.js, SceneKit, Core Bluetooth

EXPERIENCE

iOS Developer Bokadirekt

MAY. 2023 - Present, Stockholm

Freelance Developer KODA KODA

JAN. 2023 - Present, Stockholm

Lead iOS Developer BRUCE

OCT. 2019 - DEC. 2022, Stockholm

Even if developing the app was my main responsibility, I also played a big role in designing the ui/ux, leading the product development, structuring how we managed projects and improving our ways of working.

Software Engineer Doberman

JAN. 2019 - OCT. 2019, Stockholm & New York

Aida Calculus - the world's first AI enabled Calculus tutor by Pearson. Huge project spanning across three different timezones (New York, Denver and Stockholm). With over 40 people involved, I was part of the product team and led the development of the iOS application from start. Spent three months in the US.

iOS Developer Hint

APR. 2018 - DEC. 2018, Stockholm

Shareholder and responsible for developing the alpha and beta version of the app which also included an app for the watch and widgets.

iOS Developer Mobiento

JUN. 2018, Stockholm

Freelancing for a digital agency focusing on mobile where I worked with Electrolux.

iOS Developer Deedster

MAY. 2018, Stockholm

Freelancing for a startup that's fighting climate change.

iOS Developer Dashl

JAN. 2016 - MAR. 2016, Stockholm

As a freelancer I helped define, design and develop a prototype for a new beauty-startup.

iOS Developer BBH Stockholm

AUG. 2015 - APR. 2018, Stockholm & New York

Formerly Monterosa. Responsible for developing, publishing and maintaining apps while exploring new technologies. Working in teams consisting of producers, creatives, designers, testers and developers. Clients included Rebtel, Volvo & TUI among others. Spent three months with the New York office.

iOS Developer Frontcell

MAR. 2013 - AUG. 2015, Stockholm

Frontcell is a mobile agency where I worked with clients mainly focusing on Objective-C and Swift. Worked with clients like Litago, Fabege & Swedish Church.

Bartender Various bars

AUG. 2007 - AUG. 2012, Stockholm, Copenhagen & London

After high school I worked as a cocktail bartender where I developed my social skills and attention to detail.

EDUCATION

Application Development Malmö Yrkeshögskola

AUG. 2012 - MAR. 2013, Malmö

Studied Objective-C and created my first app called Happy Stream which was a radio streaming service that made it into the music top 20 on App Store. Did my internship at Frontcell which I later joined full-time.

Graphic Communication Nordic Technical Institute

SEP. 2004 - JUN. 2007, Stockholm

RECOMMENDATIONS

Joe Fraga

Senior Software Engineering Manager at Microsoft, New York

"Patrik is an excellent iOS developer. His ability to move fast and focus and to step back and look at the whole picture is remarkable. Working both in person and remotely, collaboration was always fluid, smart and humble."

Henric Malmberg

Head of Mobile Engineering at BRUCE, Stockholm

"He is a highly skilled and experienced developer with a deep understanding of the iOS platform. His expertise in Swift and UIKit, as well as his structured way of working, made him an invaluable colleague both to myself and to the rest of the team at Bruce. Patrik is not only a developer, he is also great at planning, project managing and UX design. He is proactive in identifying and solving problems, and is great to brainstorm ideas with. He is a talented developer who consistently delivers high-quality work."

Jonas Beck

Software Engineer / Team Lead at Doberman, Stockholm

"His deep knowledge of the iOS ecosystem and best practices were crucial to the project. It was a true pleasure to have Patrik on the team and I personally really enjoyed working with him both as a professional and as a person. I found him easy and fun to collaborate with and despite tight deadlines and ever changing exceptions he always kept the eye on the user value and delivered clean code. In addition to that he always looked out for improvements in our way of working, both in terms of code and processes."

Hwa Rang Na

Head of Development at Deloitte Digital, Stockholm

"Patrik is a senior developer that brings traits like accountability and high quality to the team. He is curious by nature which is showcased in finding best practices for new features or enhancing existing code base. In projects, his high standards and likable personality makes him a valuable asset both as a team member inspiring others and making sure the project generates the expected output."

Erik Agrell

Head of Technology at Doberman, Stockholm

"With his high technical skills within mobile development combined with his easy going personality, he always was a great asset to the team. Patriks most prominent personality trait is his dedication and strive to always make the best possible product no matter what it takes. Something that was always highly appreciated among the clients he worked with."